# **SERXHIO** GUGO

gugoserxhio@gmail.com

203-819-1259



https://serxhiogugo.co/



https://www.linkedin.com/in/serxhio-gugo/



https://github.com/SerxhioGugo



# EDUCATION

**IOS FNGINFFR** 

# BACHELOR'S DEGREE, COMPUTER SCIENCE

BMCC GPA: 3.8

# IOS DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP

BrainStation Bootcamp 2018 – 2019

#### SKILLS

# iOS Development

- Swift
- RESTful API's
- URLSession & Codable
- Unit Testing XCTest
- CI/CD Pipeline Fastlane Gitlab
- OOP Principles
- MVC / MVVM
- Agile/Scrum Jira/Confluence

#### FRAMEWORKS:

-UIKit, SwiftUI, Combine, AVFoundation, Core Location, MapKit Web Sockets.

#### **DATABASES:**

- CoreData
- RealmSwift
- Firebase (Auth, Storage, Firestore, FCM, Crashlytics)

#### LIBRARIES:

-AlamoFire, Moya SDWebImage, SnapKit etc.

# PROJECTS

**Cinemator**-AppStore <a href="https://apple.co/2Uwc0Ni">https://apple.co/2Uwc0Ni</a>

CryptoNews-GitHub https://bit.ly/3fqkP6e

# ABOUT

My name is Serxhio Gugo and I'm an iOS Engineer based in Connecticut, previously NYC. I'm a highly motivated engineer with 5+ years of experience programming in Swift. I am fascinated by how mobile devices and applications influence our daily lives. I have always had a passion for iOS Development or technology in general. I have a good eye for design, seeking to combine innovation and technology to build quality products.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### iOS Engineer

Caesars Digital - New Jersey / Sept 2020 - Present <a href="https://www.caesars.com/">https://www.caesars.com/</a>

- Built Registration/Login using multiple RESTful API's while implementing Email/Password/Address/Phone Number validation.
- Developed Account Menu with 16+ journeys and used Deep linking to redirect the app to different journeys from our website. Integrated Caesars Rewards into the app.
- Created completely re-usable UI for SportsBook betting and more.
- Organized the app to account for multi-state while using GeoComply and CoreLocations to identify user location.
- Properly mocked and Unit Tested all my features, which lowered our bug results by 21%.

#### iOS Engineer

Gesture - New York / Jun 2020 - Sept 2020 https://www.yourgesture.com/

- Worked closely with the back-end team to design and develop Gesture - Happiness Delivered.
- Developed Event Planning feature using Firebase Cloud Messaging and Cloud Functions.
- Developed Phone number Authentication feature using Firebase and Twilio.

#### iOS Engineer

Freelance

Client: AppCrunch LTD / Jun 2018 - May 2020

- Worked closely with the back-end team to design and develop Lollipop Dating App. Link: <a href="https://apple.co/2KYDXri">https://apple.co/2KYDXri</a>
- Develop the chat functionality of the app.
- Implement camera functionality using AVFoundation.
- Refactoring of the base code from Objective-C to the latest Swift syntax.